A Guide to the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Northern Virginia Businesses Receipts Collection, 1901-1940
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Northern Virginia Businesses Receipts Collection, 1901-1940
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 02-14
0.5 linear feet
The Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Northern Virginia Businesses Receipts Collection spans the years 1901-1940, and consists of business letterhead, receipts, correspondence, and checks from Fairfax County, Alexandria, and Washington, D.C. businesses.
Fairfax County Board of Supervisors
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection deaccessioned from the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors’ records at the Fairfax County Archives and Records Management Branch. These receipts were originally part of a larger collection that was being destroyed. They were transferred to the Virginia Room in July 2019.
Historical and Biographical Information
In July 1869, Virginia voters ratified the Underwood Constitution which required each Virginia county to divide into townships and establish a board of supervisors as the chief administrative agency. In December 1870, the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors officially took charge of county property from the court. Subsequently, bills were sent to the board for services rendered to the county such as medical attention, food, general merchandise, building and road construction or repair, and transportation of goods. This collection features a snapshot of some of the local business that carried out work for Fairfax County in the early 20th century.
Scope and Content
The Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Northern Virginia Businesses Receipts Collection spans the years 1901-1940, and consists of business letterhead, receipts, correspondence, and checks from Fairfax County, Alexandria, and Washington, D.C. businesses. These receipts were billed to the Board of Supervisors for services or goods provided to Fairfax County. The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Business enterprises - Virginia - Fairfax County
Container List
- Aitcheson & Brother, Lumber, Laths, Shingles and Building Material, Alexandria, VA, 1906 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexandria Lighting Company, Alexandria, VA, 1914 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- M.B. Alsop, Jr., Groceries and Provisions, Alexandria, VA, 1914 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Woman's Press Association, Mary M. North, Herndon, VA, 1916 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Henry Baader & Sons, Cooking and Heating Stoves, Alexandria, VA, 1918 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ballenger & Bro., General Merchandise, Alexandria, VA, 1914 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Barbour, Keith, McCandlish & Garnett and R. Walton Moore, attorneys, Fairfax, VA, 1934 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- A.D. Bauserman, Moreland Farm, Clifton Station, VA, 1917 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- D.E. Bayliss, General Contractor and Builder, Alexandria, VA, 1920 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- D.S. Beach, Groceries, Stoneleigh, VA, 1916 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Belmont Trap Rock Company, Inc. Herndon, VA, 1921-1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board of Supervisors of Fairfax County, Virginia [checks], 1901-1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bouton & Milburn, General Insurance Agents, Vienna, VA [RE: Courthouse buildings insurance], 1920 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Joseph L. Bristow, Ossian Hall, Fairfax, VA, 1928 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Charles F. Broadwater, Agricultural Implements, Wagons, Buggies, Hardware, Harness etc, Fairfax, VA, 1914 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Charles F. Broadwater, Groceries, Fairfax, VA, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- W.E. Broders, Groceries, Franconia, VA, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dr. F.M. Brooks, M.D., Swetnam, VA, 1918 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- C.E. Brown, Lumber, Springfield, VA [lumber for Cameron Run Bridge], 1916 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Buckley Brothers. General Merchandise, Clifton Station, VA, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- G.H. Burke, General Merchandise, Burkes Station, VA, 1904 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- James Campbell, M.D., Vienna, VA, 1916 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- J.B. Carter, Groceries and General Merchandise, Lincolnia, VA, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Centerville Garage, Clifton Station, VA, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Central Garage, G.H. Beavers, M.C. Weller, Fairfax, VA, 1920 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- T.E. Crowell, 1921 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- N.C. Davis, General Merchandise, Lorton, VA, 1921 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- S.H. Detwiler, Livery, Clifton Station, VA [for moving Miss Maggie Croson], 1915 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- R.H. Downs, General Merchandise, Fairfax, VA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Benjamin F. Elliott, Groceries, Falls Church, VA, 1916-1928 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- E.W. Fairfax, General Merchandise, Fairfax Station, VA, 1927 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Fairfax County Farmers Service Co., Vienna, VA, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Fairfax County Independent, Earle T. Mutersbaugh, Fairfax, VA, 1933 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Fairfax Feed & Supply Co., Miller S. Kielsgard, Fairfax, VA, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Fairfax Garage Co., W.W. Beattie, W.C. Heflin, Fairfax, VA, 1928 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Fairfax Garage and Livery, L.H. Young, Fairfax, VA, 1917-1927 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Fairfax Herald, William F. Carne, Fairfax, VA, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Fairfax Shop, Dry Goods and Notions, Fairfax, VA, 1930 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Falls Church Auto and Lumber Co., East Falls Church, VA, 1921 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Falls Church Coal & Supply Co. Inc, East Falls Church, VA, 1927 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Falls Church Telephone & Telegraph Co., Falls Church, VA, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The First National Bank of Alexandria, Alexandria, VA, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Dr. Howard Fletcher, Fairfax, VA, 1916 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Florence Crittenton Hope and Help Mission, Washington, D.C., 1919 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- C. Vernon Ford & Wilson M. Farr, Attorneys at Law, Fairfax, VA, 1921 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- L. L. Freeman, General Merchandise, Vienna, VA, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- J.E. Gheen, General Merchandise, Pender, VA, 1921-1930 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Gillespie's Filling Station, Fairfax, VA, 1927 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- E.E. Gillette, Dr., Herndon, VA, 1917 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- M.A. Gordon, General Merchandise, Fairfax, VA, 1907 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- W.R. Gray, Florist, Oakton, VA, 1918 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Miss M. Gundry, Falls Church, VA, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- W.I. Harrison, Livery Feed and Sale Stable, Herndon, VA, 1913 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Hechts' Greater Stores, Washington, D.C., 1917 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Herndon Milling Company, Inc., Herndon, VA, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- S.A. Hersperger, Dry Goods and General Merchandise, Herndon, VA, 1907 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Charles F. Holden Co., Alexandria, VA, 1920 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- C.C. Hollister, Pumps, Gasoline Engines, and Plumbing, Fairfax, VA, 1913 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Worth Hulfish & Sons, Wholesale Hardware, Alexandria, VA, 1920 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Hutchison & Mitchell Co., Inc., General Farm Supplies, Herndon, VA [RE: Scotts Run Georgetown Pike bridge], 1913 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Independent Mutual Fire Insurance Co. of Fairfax County, Va.,, 1913-1918 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- J.M. Jackson, General Merchandise, Annandale, VA, 1914 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- A.J. Kidwell, Horeshoeing General Blacksmithing, Clifton Station, VA, 1914 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Morris Legum, General Merchandise, Fairfax, VA and Vienna, VA, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Dr. Alfred Leigh, M.D., Colvin Run, VA, 1909 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- The Liverpool & London & Glove Insurance Company, Ltd. Herndon, VA [RE: Courthouse buildings insurance], 1920 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Vernon M. Lynch, Elmdale Farms, Alexandria, VA, 1928 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Miss Madeira's School, Lucy Madeira Wing, Washington, D.C., 1931 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Dr. A.F. Malcom, Veterinary Surgeon, Occoquan, VA, 1930 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- William McCauley, Plumbing Heating and Gas Fitting, East Falls Church, VA, 1916 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- W.M. McNair, Bread Meal, Graham Flour, Feed Meal, Herndon, VA [crushed rock for Cub Run Bridge], 1916 December (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Menin, Passin & Co., General Merchandise, Fairfax, VA, 1913 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Murphy & Ames, Inc. Lumber and Mill Work, East Falls Church, VA, 1928 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Loudoun County, Waterford, VA, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Loudoun, L. L. Freeman agent, Vienna, VA [RE: Courthouse buildings insurance], 1920 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- The National Bank of Fairfax, Fairfax, VA, 1906-1940 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- The National Bank of Herndon, Herndon, VA, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- James E. Nickell, General Hardware, Fairfax, VA, 1921-1928 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Nickell & Huffard, General Hardware, Paints & Oils, Fairfax, VA, 1927 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- P.B Nourse, Livery, Feed and Sale Stables, East Falls Church, VA, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Oakton Cash Store, J.W. Sutton, General Merchandise, Oakton, VA, 1918 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- The Observer, G.R. Sims, Herndon, VA, 1920 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- E.H. Oliver, General Merchandise, Alexandria, VA, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Mrs. John E. Oliver, General Merchandise, Vienna, VA and Kenmore, VA, 1930 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- C.J. Parkinson & Co., General Merchandise, Oakton, VA, 1914 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Penn Daw Hotel, S. Cooper Dawson, Alexandria, VA, 1931 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- George K. Pickett, Real Estate, Insurance and Bonding, Alexandria, VA, 1928 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- B.L. Poole, Veterinary Surgeon, Herndon, VA, 1930 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- W.T. Ralston, Grocery and Meat Market, Fairfax, VA, 1930 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- I.G. Robertson, Wheelwright and Blacksmith, Fairfax, VA, 1918 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Ernest L. Robey, Druggist, Fairfax, VA, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- W. H. Rogers, Carpenter and Builder, Falls Church, VA, 1918 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Rosslyn Milling Corporation, Rosslyn, VA, 1920 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Royal Insurance Company Limited of Liverpool Agency at Fairfax, VA [RE: Courthouse buildings insurance], 1920 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- John H. Ruff, Delco-Light Products, Fairfax, VA, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- H.G. Sauls, Groceries, Fairfax, VA, 1921 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- J.F. Scheffel & Son, Contractors, Herndon, VA [Waple Mill & Hickory Run bridge], 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- John C. Sisson, General Auto Repairing, Fairfax, VA, 1927 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- W.A. Smoot & Co., Inc., Alexandria, VA, 1920 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- I.E. Stalcup, Groceries and General Merchandise, Chesterbrook, VA, 1929 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- C. L. Starkweather, M.D., Occoquan, VA [Harvey Pearson inquest], 1909 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- R.W. Stump, Herndon, VA, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Dr. Ford Swetnam, Vienna, VA, 1918 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Taylor's Pharmacy, T. Ramsay Taylor, Fairfax, VA, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- L.M. Thompson, Fairfax, VA, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- T.J. Thompson, Tinner and Plumber, Fairfax, VA, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Thompson & Seamans, Lumber and Railroad Ties, Herndon, VA, 1923 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Thornton & Thornton, Attorneys at Law, Fairfax, VA, 1902 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- A.R. Tracy, Electrical Engineer, East Falls Church, VA, 1913 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- George R. L. Turberville Department Store, Centreville, VA, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- Enos Utterback, Centreville, VA [soft drink license], Undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
- The Virginia Hotel Company, Fairfax, VA, 1916 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Virginia Midland Railway, Alexandria, VA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Waggoner Bros., Automobile Repairing, Vienna, VA, 1921 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- Walter A. Warfield, M.D., Alexandria, VA, 1916 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- Washington and Old Dominion Railway, Vienna, VA, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Washington Virginia Railway Co., Vienna, VA, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- J.B. Webster, General Merchandise, Lorton, VA, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 118)
- V.V. Weaver, General Merchandise, Clifton Station, VA, 1927 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Wheeler Milling Company, Browns Chapel, VA, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 120)
- Dr. Jack B. Zerbee, Fairfax, VA, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 121)